Guide to the Florine Stettheimer Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Florine Stettheimer Papers,
[ca. 1920]-1940
Stettheimer, Florine, 1871-1944.
ca. 900 items (7 boxes, 40 v., 1 portfolio)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079368
Biographical Note
American artist, theatrical set designer. Stettheimer is perhaps best known for the lavish sets and costumes she designed for the first American production, in 1934, of Gertrude Stein's opera Four Saints In Three Acts, with music by Virgil Thomson.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, scrapbooks of clippings and photographs, reproductions of art works, two portfolios of original drawings, and the puppets for Stein's opera Four Saints In Three Acts.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 8 series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Manuscripts
Series III: Original artwork by Stettheimer
Series IV: Original artwork (not by Stettheimer)
Series V: Scrapbook
Series VI: Photographs
Series VII: Printed Material
Series VIII: Audio Visual
Subjects
Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989.; Puppet plays.; Operas--United States.; Theaters--Stage-setting and scenery.; Costume.; Photoprints.; Scrapbooks.; Drawings.; Women artists.; Set designers.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located on-site.
Acquisition
1967 M-67 Solomon, Joseph Gift
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Penelope Redd To Florine Stettheimer, [n.p.], May 13, 1922, (1 t.n.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - H.E. Schnakenberg To Florine Stettheimer, [n.p.], December 10, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Glenway Wescott To Ettie Stettheimer, [n.p.], November 21, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    [Including a copy of his letter to the editor of "Art News" and draft of her reply]
  - Mr. and Mrs. Nelson Rockefeller To Ettie Stettheimer, [N.Y.], October, [n.y.] (Box 1, Folder 4)
    [Invitation to dinner preceeding the opening of the Florine Stettheimer Exhibition October 1st, [n.d]]
  - Donald Gallup To Joseph Solomon, [n.p.], January 23, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virgil Thomson To Jane Sabersky, [n.p.], February 24, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Joseph Solomon To Jane Sabersky, [n.p.], September 18, 1973 (Box 4)
    [Enclosed in View Magazine]
- Series II: Manuscripts
  - Names of artists, [n.p.], [n.d], (5 sheets, 1 sketch) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - List of Stettheimer's paintings and their dates, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 sheets) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - List of people in painting 'Duchamp's Birthday' and partial list of people in painting 'Cathedral Wall Street', [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 sheets) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - MOMA exhibit [1946], [N.Y.], [ca.1946], (127 Typed and handwritten 3 x 5 in. cards) (Box 6)
- Series III: Original artwork by Stettheimer
  - Subseries III.1: Unbound
    - Watercolored cards, [n.p.], [n.d.], (28 cards, 4.5 x 3.5 in) (Box 1, Folder 1a & 1b)
      [With note that cards made at school for fortune-telling]
    - House, landscape designs, portraits, [n.p.], [n.d.], (11 watercolors) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Pocahontas-notes on Pocahontas' life and sketches for the ballet, including props and costumes, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 3a-3c)
    - Pencil and ink sketches of furniture and frame design, with some notes. Includes photograph of a frame and side table designed by Stettheimer, [n.p.], [n.d.], (66 ) (Box 1, Folder 4a-4c)
    - Sketches of Roman Catholic ceremonies, [n.p.], 1900?, (6 Pencil, watercolor and pastel) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Studies of European landscapes, with notes on entrances to Royal Court of England, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 watercolor) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Study for portrait of Carrie Stettheimer, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 watercolor, pencil) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Study of Picadilly and New York, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 watercolor, pencil) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Sketches and notebook of Tarrytown, zoo in parks, [N.Y.], [n.d.], (2 pencil) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sketch of mother; another sketch on reverse, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 charcoal) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Landscapes: Dinard, Starnbergersee, Barbizon, Etretat, harbor and beach scenes, [v.p.], [n.d.], (10: 9.5 x 13 in. Paintings on wood) (Box 1, Folder 11-20)
    - Landscapes: Lac de Geneve, Chamonix? Vulpera, [v.p.], [n.d.], (3 Painted canvas) (Box 210)
  - Subseries III.2: Journals
    - Notes and sketches on European artists and patrons; tombs and cathedrals; chair frame; ornament design; cut out of frames, [n.p.], [n.d.] (Box 208)
      [Should be unfolded]
    - Sketches, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Pencil, watercolor, pastel) (Box 208)
      [mostly empty]
    - Sketches, Rome, [n.d.], (Pencil, charcoal, watercolor, mixed) (Box 210)
      [filled]
    - Flowers. Landscapes of a park, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 separated leaf Pencil, watercolor, Entire journal pencil, watercolor, charcoal) (Box 269)
      [mostly filled; poorly bound]
    - Landscape sketches, Vulpera (Switzerland), [n.d.], (Pencil, watercolor) (Box 210)
    - Florine's artwork, exhibition notices and catalogues, newspaper reviews and notices, 1922-1924?, (Photographs, printed material) (Box 212)
      [disbound scrapbook.]
    - Landscapes and portraits, Tyrol, Salzburg, Bavaria, [n.d.], (Pencil, crayon) (Box 209)
      [filled. Includes 2 unbound watercolors]
    - Landscapes, Andirondacks, NY, 1904-5, (Pencil, charcoal, watercolor, crayon) (Box 209)
      [mostly filled]
    - Landscapes: Thirn? Gurnigelbad (Switz.) Biarritz, Evian, Lucerne, [v.p.], 1914, (Pencil, watercolor, crayon) (Box 209)
    - Landscapes and figures, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Pencil, watercolor) (Box 209)
    - Women in various poses, 1908-9, (Pencil, watercolor) (Box 210)
      [mostly filled. Includes 2 loose sheets]
    - Lakes, cityscapes, parks, villas, Italy, [n.d.], (Pencil, watercolor) (Box 210)
      [partly filled]
    - Landscapes, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Pencil, watercolor) (Box 208)
      [half filled]
    - Landscapes, Vulpera (Switzerland), [n.d.], (Pencil, charcoal, watercolor) (Box 210)
    - Landscapes, Berncastel, the Mosel, etc., 1910-1912[?], (Pencil, watercolor) (Box 208)
    - Landscapes, portraits, architectural details, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Pencil, pen, crayon) (Box 208)
    - Landscapes and portraits, Venice[?], [n.d.], (Pencil, watercolor) (Box 210)
      [mostly filled. Includes three loose pencil and crayon landscapes]
    - Florine's schoolgirl productions, sketches of people, some labeled, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Pencil, watercolor) (Box 208)
    - Florine Stettheimer's various apartments, Bryant Park Studios (Beaux Arts) 80 W. 40th Street, NYC and Alwyn Court, 58th and 7th Ave., NYC, [n.d.], (Photographs) (Box 211)
      [some missing, some labeled]
    - Costume designs in pencil and watercolor. Sketches of costume and set design, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 Pencil, watercolor) (Box 209)
      [Partly filled; 4 have come loose]
    - Drawings made from ages 12-16, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Pencil) (Box 269)
      [Loose sheets. All signed.]
    - Portraits, [n.p.], [n.d.], (Watercolor) (Box 208)
      [Loose sheets. Seem very early]
  - Subseries III.3: Figurines
    - Figurines for Pocahontas, [n.p.], [n.d], (8 figurines Wire, crepe paper, thread, feathers, cellophane) (Box 205)
    - Figurines for Pocahontas, [n.d], (14 figurines Wire, crepe paper, thread, feathers, cellophane) (Box 206)
    - Props for Four Saints in Three Acts, [n.d], (Coral, metal, cloth, toile and feathers) (Box 206)
    - Figurines for Four Saints in Three Acts, 1934, (26 figurines Wire, crepe paper, thread, feathers, velvet, toile, feather, cellophane) (Box 207)
    - Materials used in the creation of the figurines, [n.d], (ca. 10 items Blue cellophane, cloth, feathers, lace) (Box 5)
      [Used for making figurines]
- Series IV: Original artwork (not by Stettheimer)
  - Weller Landscape, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 Painted canvas) (Box 269)
- Series V: Scrapbook
  - No. 1: Photographs of artwork, printed notices, catalogues and articles about exhibitions, ca. 1916-1922, (Photographs, printed materials) (Box 212)
- Series VI: Photographs
  Some photographs have multiple copies and might be found in more than one location. The count indicated is often for all of the items in both locations.
  - Subseries VI.1: Stettheimer's work
    - "Landscape with Trees", [1901?], (1 Photograph) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Spring", 1907, (1 Photograph) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Spring", 1907, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Head of Medusa", 1908, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Scenario for ballet, "Orphee of the Quat'z Arts", c. 1912, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Still Life number 1 with Flowers" or "Flowers against Wallpaper", 1915, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Still Life number 1 with Flowers" or "Flowers against Wallpaper", 1915, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Flowers number 3 Against BlueGreen (Shallow Bowl)", c. 1915, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Family Portrait number 1", 1915, (7 [total] Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Family Portrait number 1", 1915, (7 [total] Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Andre Brook-front", 1915, (4 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Andre Brook-front", 1915, (4 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Andre Brook-back", 1915, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Andre Brook-back", 1915, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Portrait of Avery Hopwood", 1915-16, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Nude/Self-Portrait", c. 1915-16, (4 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Nude/Self-Portrait", c. 1915-16, (4 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Jenny and Genevieve", [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      [exhibited in 1916)]
    - "Jenny and Genevieve", [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Flowers with a Parrot", 1916, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Flowers with a Parrot", 1916, (3 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Flowers with a Parrots (portrait painted out)", 1916, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Tulips with Curtain" or "Flowers number 4: early version", 1916, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Tulips with Curtain" or "Flowers number 4", 1916?, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Flowers with Aphrodite", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      [exhibited in 1916]
    - "Flowers with Aphrodite", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Flowers in Two Bowls: tall thin white and low decorated white", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      [exhibited in1916?]
    - "Flowers in Two Bowls: tall thin white and low decorated white", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Mixed Flowers in Tall White Bowl", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      [exhibited 1916?]
    - "Mixed Flowers in Tall White Bowl", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Woman Arranging Flowers in White Bowl", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      [exhibited 1916-17]
    - "Woman Arranging Flowers in White Bowl", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Mixed flowers in White Shallow Bowl", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Mixed flowers in White Shallow Bowl", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Eastern Picture", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      [exhibited in 1916?]
    - "Eastern Picture", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Sunday Afternoon in the Country", 1917, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "West Point", 1917, (4 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "West Point", 1917, (4 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "La Fete A Duchamps", 1917, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      [with attached description]
    - "La Fete A Duchamps", 1917, (2 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Soiree" or "Studio Party", 1917-19, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Soiree" or "Studio Party", 1917-19, (2 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Heat", 1918, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Heat", 1918, (3 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Picnic at Bedford Hills", 1918, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Picnic at Bedford Hills", 1918, (3 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "New York 1918", 1918, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "New York 1918", 1918, (2 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "7 Flowers in White Vase under a Canopy", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
      [exhibited Society of Independents, 1918]
    - "Lake Placid", 1919, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Lake Placid", 1919, (3 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Asbury Park South", 1920, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Asbury Park South", 1920, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Asbury Park South, showing water damage, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Music", c. 1920, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Portrait of Adolfo Best-Maugard", post-1920, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Spring Sale at Bendels", 1921, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Spring Sale at Bendels", 1921, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Flower Bouquet number 1" or "Easter Bouquet, c. 1921, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Flower Bouquet number 1" or "Easter Bouquet, c. 1921, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Flower Bouquet number 2" or "Cornucopia of Flowers", c.1921, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Flowers in a Cup/Flowers no. 9", c. 1921, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Russian Bank", 1921, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Russian Bank", 1921, (3 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Portrait of Carl Van Vechten", 1922, (4 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Portrait of Carl Van Vechten", 1922, (4 Photographs) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Portrait of Henry McBride", 1922, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Fourfold Decorative Panel of Stettheimer Family", [n.d. (exhibited in 1922)], (1 photograph of Florin's panel in Box 2; 1 complete set in Journal no. 6 ) (Box 2, Folder 2)
      [1 complete set in Journal no. 6]
    - "Fourfold Decorative Panel of Stettheimer Family", [n.d. (exhibited in 1922)], (1 photograph of Florin's panel in Box 2; 1 complete set in Journal no. 6 ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Fire Screen with Persiana", [c. 1922], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Portrait of Myself", 1923, (1 negative ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Myself", 1923, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of My Sister, Ettie Stettheimer", 1923, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of my Sister, Carrie W. Stettheimer with Doll's House", 1923, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Marcel Duchamp", 1923, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Louis Bouche", 1923, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Louis Bouche", 1923, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Portrait of Joseph Hergesheimer", 1923, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Joseph Hergesheimer", 1923, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Portrait of Baron de Meyer", 1923, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Louis Bernheimer", 1923, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Louis Bernheimer", 1923, (1 photograph ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Our Neighbors number 1", 1923, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Our Neighbors no. 2", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Beauty Contest: to the memory of P.T. Barnum", 1924, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of my Mother", 1925, (5 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Bouquet for Ettie" or "Flowers with Blue Curtain", 1927, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Natatorium Undine", 1927, (4 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Fourth of July number 1", 1927, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Fourth of July number 2", 1927, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Three Flowers" or "Journey to the Sun", c. 1927, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Three Flowers and a Dragonfly", 1928, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Padre Carlos Westend", 1928, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of my Aunt, Caroline Walter Neustater", 1928, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Portrait of Alfred Steiglitz", 1928, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Cathedrals of Broadway", 1929, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Portrait of Our Nurse, Margaret Burgess", 1929, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Portrait of my Teacher in Stuttgart, Fraulein von Preiser", 1929, (8 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "My Birthday Eyegay", 1929, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Love Flight of a Pink Candy Heart", 1930, (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Sun", 1931, (7 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Cathedrals of 5th Avenue", 1931, (8 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Birthday Bouquet/Flowers with Snake", 1932, (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Family Portrait number 2", 1933, (8 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Spring 1932/Portrait of the Dancer, Olin Howland", 1933, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Cathedrals of Wall Street", 1939, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Cathedrals of Art", 1942 (unfinished), (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Cathedrals of Art" detail, 1942, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Four Flowers and a Dragonfly", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Phlox: Verbena and Yellow Daisies", [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
      [is this Still Life with Flowers, c. 1921?]
    - "Five Flower Bouquet/Cornucopia of Flowers", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Flowers number 6", [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Flowers with Japanese Print", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Flowers with White Curtain--Spring Bouquet", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
      [is this Morning?]
    - "Flowers number 5" or "Spring Bouquet", [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Zinnias" or "Flowers in White Bowl with drape festoon", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "12 Flowers under a canopy", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Mars figure", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Stettheimer Memorial Exhibition at the MOMA, 1946, (7 Photographs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Subseries VI.2: Artwork other than Stettheimer's
    - Carl Sprinchorn 'Chair with Fruit and a Parrot', 1926, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Carl Sprinchorn Portrait of a woman, unknown, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Adolfo Best-Maugard Portrait of Henrie Waste (Ettie Stettheimer), 1920, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bradley Duli? Portrait of a woman, 1833, (1 photograph ) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Classical and early modern artwork, sculptures and paintings, [n.p.], [n.d.], (32 and prints Photographs) (Box 2, Folder Folders 9a-9c)
  - Subseries VI.3: Stettheimer apartments
    - Florine's apartments and studio, New York, [n.d.], (27 Photographs) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Family apartment at Alwyn Court, New York, 1926-35, (3 Photographs) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Interior on Hohenstaufen Strasse, Munich, 1912-13, (2 Photographs) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Florine's studio on W. 40th St. and Alwyn Court, New York, [n.d.] (Box 211, Folder No. 19)
  - Subseries VI.4: Carrie Stettheimer's dollhouse
    - Interiors and exterior of the dollhouse, including Gallery of Masterpieces, [n.p.], [n.d.], (13 Photographs) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - The dollhouse [Carrie Stettheimer], Museum of the City of New York, [n.d.], (1 postcard) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Subseries VI.5: Family and friends
    - Mielziner, artist Ettie Stettheimer?portrait, 1916, (2 charcoal Photographs) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Arnold Genthe, photographer Ettie Stettheimer, NY, [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Arnold Genthe, photographer Ettie Stettheimer portrait, NY, [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Florine Stettheimer Portrait of Stettheimer, leaning on sundial, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Florine Stettheimer Portrait of Florine Stettheimer in a flowered dress in the woods, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Carrie Stettheimer Portrait of Carrie Stettheimer in Red Cross uniform, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph ) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Carrie Stettheimer Portrait of Carrie Stettheimer in Red Cross uniform, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 Photographs) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series VII: Printed Material
  Some notices, catalogues and articles have multiple copies and might be found in more than one location
  - Subseries VII.1: Exhibition/performance notices and invitations
    - "Exhibition of Paintings by Miss Florine Stettheimer", Mssrs. M. Knoedler & Co., October 16-28, 1916 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Exhibition of Paintings and Drawings Showing the Later Tendencies in Art", Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts, Philadelphia, April 16-May 15, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Retrospective Exhibition of American Art", Junior Art Patrons of America, May 6-21, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Exhibition of Contemporary American Art, Modern Artists of America, Inc.", Galleries of Joseph Brummer, April 1-30, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Exhibition of Contemporary American Art, Modern Artists of America, Inc.", Galleries of Joseph Brummer, April 1-30, 1922 (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
    - "Annual American Exhibition at the Wanamaker Gallery of Modern Decorative Arts", Wanamaker Gallery, Belmaison, January 22-February 17, 1923 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Sarah Newmeyer "Museum of Modern Art Opens Large Exhibition of Paintings by Florine Stettheimer" (MOMA press release), Museum of Modern Art, [c.1946] (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Invitation from the Arts Club of Chicago for two exhibitions: Andre Derain and Florine Stettheimer", Arts Club, Chicago, January 3, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Invitation for opening of the Alfred Stieglitz Collection of Modern Art for Fisk University and the Florine Stettheimer Memorial Collection of Books about the Fine Arts", Fisk University, November 4, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Playbill for Four Saints in Three Acts, The Broadway Theatre, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Circulating Exhibitions at the MOMA, 1953-4", [New York], 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Exhibition at Mrs. Brumback's 12th Street Gallery", Mrs. Brumback's 12th Street Gallery, February 18-March 5,[n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "Second Annual Decorative Exhibition in Wanamaker Gallery of Modern Decorative Art", Wanamaker Gallery, Belmaison, March 1-21,[n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Second Annual Decorative Exhibition in Wanamaker Gallery of Modern Decorative Art", Wanamaker Gallery, Belmaison, March 1-21,[n.d.] (Box 212, Folder No. 6)
  - Subseries VII.2: Catalogues
    - First Annual Exhibition of the Society of Independent Artists, April 10-May 6, 1917, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Second Annual Exhibition of the Society of Independent Artists, April 20-May 12, 1918, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Third Annual Exhibition of the Society of Independent Artists, March 28-April 14, 1919, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - Fourth Annual Exhibition of the Society of Independent Artists, March 11-April 1, 1920, (partial ) (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Exhibition of Modern Art by Contemporary Artists", Worcester Art Museum, April 25-May 16, 1920 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)
    - "Suggestions for the Decoration of the Fireplace", The Arts Guild Galleries, April 11-23, 1921 (Box 212, Folder No. 1)